## Phil Tsarik

Highly motivated person with 4+ years experience in a front end and back end development. Broad experience in working with web front end tools and frameworks (e.g jQuery, AngularJS) as well as with pure JavaScript and HTML/CSS in modern and old browsers and different platforms. Experienced in developing of full stack web-applications using Ruby and Java.

#### **Contacts:**

• Tel: +375 29 2181503

• Email: phil.tsarik@gmail.com

• Skype: phil.tsarik

• My legal name: Pilip Tsaryk

#### Skills

- Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Python, Bash, Java, Android, SQL, PostgreSQL, UML
- HTML/CSS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Ajax, Sass, ExtJS, jQuery

## Experience

• JavaScript Developer, Nov 2015–Present

Developing a web-application for managing some specific hierarchy data which allows adding, removing, sorting, merging, exporting to Excel files, etc.

- Company: EPAM Systems, Krakw Area, Poland
- Responsibilities: UI development, writing automated tests, manual testing, taking part in meetings, architecture and UI design, making mockups, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: JavaScript, ECMAScript 6, AngularJS, Underscore, Gulp, Bower, Karma, Jasmine, Protractor, Git, Jira
- JavaScript Developer, Apr 2014–Oct 2015

Developing a client application for monitoring remote servers including separate versions for desktop and mobile browsers.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, UI development, manual testing, taking part in meetings, UI design, making mockups, reporting

Tools & technologies used: JavaScript, Sencha Ext JS, Sencha Touch, SASS, SCCI protocol, Sencha Architect

#### • Ruby Developer, Oct 2012–Feb 2014

Developing a firmware with Web GUI for network-attached storages based on Debian GNU/Linux. Developed and released a complete product with periodical updates with fixes and improvements.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, UI and backend development, writing automated tests, manual testing, taking part in meetings, architecture and UI design, making mockups, collaborating with translators, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: Debian, Ruby, Sinatra, Rspec, Haml, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Dropbox SDK, Jasmine, Git, Jenkins, Transifex, Jira
- Java Developer, Nov 2011–Sep 2012, Mar 2014–Apr 2014

Developing client-server application providing remote management and configuration of servers. Also taking part in a developing of an Event Service for VMWare vCenter.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, DB design, developing, testing, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: Java SE, Java RMI, Swing, JAXB, Windows PowerShell, Hibernate, Spring, Apache, H2 database, JUnit, Maven, Git, SVN
- Ruby on Rails Developer, Feb 2011–Aug 2012

Taking part in developing of a language learning service Langaroo.

- Responsibilities: UI and backend development, writing automated tests, manual testing
- Tools & technologies used: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, ERB, SASS, Compass, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Git

### Education

• Polotsk State University, 2006–2011 Diploma in Software Engineering.

# **Appendix**

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/tsarik
- https://github.com/phts